yeah I think it was right here dude this
this is what I'm talking about Kevin
when when I am reading articles this is
exactly the kind of [__] that I want to
[Music]
see best part of acing when you can just
you know critical
[Music]
thing yeah dud
all right Mr Kevin Mizu the the master
of Dom purify thank you for gracing us
with your presence here on ctpv
podcast um yeah it's a pleasure to being
there um I can't wait to speak about
them perfi today awesome dude you've
been doing great work on the uh critical
thinking research lab as well it's been
a pleasure to have you in there and when
I saw you write this stuff up and
release it I had the pleasure of of
pre-reading it and as I was reading
through I was like trying to stay
focused on like being a good proof
reader and like trying to find you know
oh maybe we should reward this reward
that but as I'm reading I'm like oh my
God that's really oh my god oh man I
kept getting distracted by the content
so um great great work on this article
really and uh you know like I said in
the chat I just I wanted to devote a
whole episode to this because D purify
is so widely used in so many different
uh you know applications and um and what
you wrote up here the F the don't get me
wrong Kevin the first article was
amazing right absolutely amazing but the
second article is like wow this is so
applicable for a bug Bounty Hunter
because these misconfigurations are what
bug bounty hunters live off of right
that's where we that's where we live um
so I was really excited to talk about
both of them um but first we gotta gotta
cut your teeth in the bug in the ctbb
podcast world we got to start off with a
a bug that you're really proud of um so
what what bug did you bring for us today
um well so I think it's probably the bug
that I'm the most Pro off that I found
recently uh it's a c side chain um so I
will try to explain it a bit quickly but
uh I had like um a gadget which allows
me to have an account takeover on the
main application of a website um but it
do requires me to have control over
cookies so I need to find somehow a
cookie injection or simply an xss on a
subdomain and after looking a bit uh
through all the sub domain of that
website I found one which had a get
parameter which was using in a fetch
request but this PCH request has to be
same same origin so you still be Li
limitated by the feature which is
present on the application itself um and
the respon of that petch request was
finishing in a document. WR sync so okay
promising it's mostly an xss as a
feature uh but the problem was that um
that application only have two rots
which was doing anything I mean there is
no feature related to it except the xss
and I have no F PL feature no IPI
nothing that can actually use to to have
a
bug so after playing a bit with it I um
found that the application was hosted
behind Cloud flare and after playing a
bit with the CDN CGI image end
points I I found that that application
was uh actually having um another uh
domain which was historically used and
that specific domain was still AOW in
the cloud flare configuration okay that
that's great how did you how did you
identify that how did you find that
honestly I was a bit like lazy and I
took the top 100 uh websites or
something like that just a
just award list on internet try to fle
of them and luckily I found one but no
way wow that's awesome that's great it
was really lucky honestly
and when I found that domain I saw that
I was able to use not only the main
domain of uh the historical one but also
all the subdomain related to it and yes
thanks to this I managed to find an
ident file upload feature which allows
me to um use an image that I control on
the CDN CGI um
endpoint so in short thank to this I was
able to make a fetch request to SN CGI
which returns me an image that I control
which contain ints in the exif an HTML
payload and then when it's uh get
consumed by document. write it the PNG
get converted to HTML which create an
exory wow okay okay okay so I I see that
I'm looking at the dock right now
there's 14 bullet points under this bug
and so and we're about halfway through
right now so let me take a second to
summarize
so let correct me if I got any part of
this wrong okay so we find this this
gadget on a subdomain and we go
specifically looking for this gadget
because we have a session fixation based
ATO we we we find this gadget on the
subdomain that allows you to control the
destination of a fetch request and that
fetch request output is just dumped
directly into document. write but it has
to be same origin so there's there's no
other on this so we hit the CDN uh CGI
image endpoint which is a part of cloud
flare which allows you to retrieve an
image from a a different server um but
it's limited to just a specific set of
domains which you enumerated by brute
forcing and then you find a place in in
that domain where you can upload a file
and put HTML data inside of the xif
metadata for that file and then you hit
that via the fetch request it D into
document. right is that right yep oh my
dude oh my God that's amazing it's crazy
to me that that I'm sorry I'm getting
derailed but but it's crazy to me that
that the CDN CGI endpoint doesn't strip
like that that metadata or those those
tag like at least HTML tags like I I
feel like that would be a good security
feature for them to implement but if
anybody from cloud Flair is listening to
this don't do that do not Implement that
um what what do you think about that
um I think it's complicated because
there is so many way to hide like
Charles within an image and S characters
could be like um legitim there is maybe
some way that an image needs to have s
tags within it so it's true yeah or like
svgs as well right like if they
legitimate svgs you can't just like
replace the left bra bracket or whatever
left angle bracket okay all right so
then we hit that but you run into a CSP
it seems right yep so so the the CSP
bypass wasn't really um difficult
actually I simply used the angular GS
Gadget and I was able to have the xss
nice so it's not really the the most
important part of U of the bypass but
thanks to the xss which was on a
completely useless domain I was finally
able to uh end that chain which was I
think very interesting in the end um so
the login feature of the main website
was using uh some something interesting
which was when you go on the login page
you get redirected to a specific page
which has in the link uv4 so you can't
reinforce it okay and that uid is
associated with two cookies one session
cookies with um which has a specific
value and another one which is prefixed
with double uncore host Dash which has
the same value okay and The Dore host
cookies is like not something that you
want to see when you want perform a
session fixation because you can't set
it um through JavaScript right right
that has to be that's an HTTP only one I
think yeah um and not Le it's um I think
it's a reserv it prefix so it absolutely
can't be set from the JavaScript not at
all yeah yeah absolutely
yeah and so to abuse that I I mean there
is something that I need to explain
first because if you have like two
clients um which has the exact same
configuration like the same uid the same
station cookies and one of them
authenticates on uh the application then
the the the first one or the second one
just need to refresh the page to be
authenticated as well ah okay it was
like a very interesting Weir bug yeah
yeah yeah so the only thing that I was
uh needing to do is finding a way to
force the victim to have the same setup
as I
do and to do that I wasn't able to
directly do session fixation because the
session cookie was set for something
like a year and has the pr priority over
mine but after playing a bit with the
application I've thought that uh if you
go like on any path like SL a MH with uh
two session cookie with different value
then the application will detect that um
something wrong is actually happening
maybe it detect that it is an attack
actually and it will try to remove the
cookies on the top level domain because
this is the only way for the browser to
have to cookie in the same
time but the problem when you try to do
that is that if you do a set cookie with
an empty value you need to have the
exact cookie configuration to remove it
with the domain the path right exactly
so if you try to remove the cookie on
sled but it has been set on sled a it
won't work at all m m so to bypass this
the application was trying to guess the
path on which it has been set and to do
that it was simply taking the request
URL provided by the user and putting it
uh in the set cookie head ah okay so
okay what I was able to do is simply
going doing a session fixation going on
slash semicolon domain equal semicolon
and that way I was able to force the
application not to remove my cookie but
the one from the user nice that's
amazing that's so
good very good so now you've got your
your uh session fixated on there and
then on the first cookie but I was still
needing to find a way to control the
second one with the the bend dusar H
cookie right with the prefix because you
can't set it from JavaScript but
actually this one wasn't too hard to uh
like uh said because when you go on a
login page with a a valid uid link to a
validation value if you don't provide
the double uncore host cookie um the
application will detect that something
is going wrong but it will suppose that
you are going you are doing something
like um legitimate so you are trying to
L in with the the correct value so it
will say like oh you're missing that
cookie let me set this cookie to the
right value that you need let me just
help for you oh my exactly so so I was
just needing to do a post request cross
site uh with the session cookie with
site none and that way everything was
ready I just need to wait the user to
log into his account and refresh my page
to get an cont take of wow very cool man
that that is an amazing bug lots of
cookie cookie quirks crazy creative xss
I love it dude I love it you you have
established uh your Authority now to
speak on the CV podcast after that bug
for sure I I I do have a question about
it though um and and this is just I
can't pull it out of my head I'm
wondering if we could have done anything
with um with cookie jar overflows here
where you could force that
host cookie and force the original
cookie out of the cookie jar and then
and then you know just fixate your your
stuff did did you try that or did it
occur to you because I don't remember if
underscore host can be affected by that
attack I didn't but for T reason because
first I think that uh cookie jar
overflow only works in if you set
cookies on the actual domain on which
you would you want to do the attack you
can't do that cross domain yeah I I
think okay and the second reason is that
uh since from a post request I was able
to have like the exact configuration I
was needing I don't even try to do that
yeah yeah okay that makes sense yeah I'm
gonna I'm gonna have to research that
because because cookie jar overflow
would be a little bit more helpful if we
could yeah just delete cookies like if I
had an exit test on subdomain site.com
if I could delete cookies for site.com
that would be pretty helpful with the
cookie chart it amazing but honestly if
you if you do manage to do that I think
it will be a chromium zero day to be H
oh really oh jeez okay yes because
there's supposed to be some boundary
between uh different sites even if they
are same s so I might be wrong but but
but it's just interesting because like
the reason the cookie jar overflow works
is is because you're pushing you know
those cookies out of storage right so I
I don't understand how I guess maybe the
storage is segmented a little bit
different by sight perhaps that's what's
going on it's segmented by site and even
so it can send more cookies than are in
the cookie jar to the server but it it
can't store those in that same site
cookie jar okay okay that that makes
sense I'm gonna validate that after this
though um all right very cool so let's
let's um let's go ahead and jump into uh
now we now we do things a little weird
here on ctbb podcast okay now we're
going to jump back Kevin Mizu I said
your name who are you what do you work
for you know what what what are you up
to in life right now man um So currently
I finished my studies something like a
year ago okay I'm working in a small
fretch company called bsecure in which
I'm doing mostly pen tests and web aits
and um on my free time I'm doing some
research some development like on
d++ and when I finally have some time
I'm doing bamb boo actually but I I
prefer to focus on research and um
developing stuff yeah dude it's it's
been great to see your research come
through and and I'm really excited for
some of the stuff you're building from
an automation perspective obviously you
know Dom lugger Plus+ yeah is a
masterpiece um and I love it but also
you've got some really cool um sort of
JS and headless browser based automation
you're working on right now yep which
I'm excited to see come out soon um but
yeah no and and to be honest dude that
um D purify or not D purify the Dum
logger Plus+ master class that we did
for for the the Pod was like one of my
favorite
master classes we've ever done that was
just so fun and so insightful so thank
you so much for doing that now you're
now you're a guest in the master classes
and a guest on the Pod so um definitely
excited for that um all right let's go
ahead and jump into um the main topic
for today which is Dom purify uh and
it's its various misconfigurations and
bypasses um Kevin did a two article
series on D purify and the research that
he put into d ver ify on his blog meu.
re which if you haven't subscribed to
you should and definitely go follow him
on Twitter at Kevin Mizu um and so the
these articles were broken out into two
um two articles the first one was mostly
just focused on on research and uh the
the Dum purify bypasses that uh that you
worked on and that other people have
worked on sort of documenting the sort
of state-of-the-art as far as D purify
bypasses go and then the second one was
taking that research and then building
on upon it with
misconfigurations and um taking some of
the knowledge from um the the research
that was done in the beginning and
applying those with misconfigurations to
find ways to exploit D purify in you
know really Hands-On production
environments um and when I when I hit
you up about this I told you we were
gonna do we're gonna do things a little
weird you know like first we jump into
the bug then we go into the introduction
and we're gonna skip we're gonna skip to
the end to um first talk about the Dom
purify misconfigurations and the reason
we're doing this is because
um listen guys I'm a I am a client side
guy I love client side stuff I I I don't
profess to be a particular expert in
mutation xss right which is a lot of
what this is but that first article is
dense guys um and and it is tricky to it
don't get me wrong Kevin it is it is
amazingly done especially with the way
you embedded all of the um you know D
stuff into what's the name of that that
thing from yes we hack that you uh Dum
Explorer has been deved by B I love that
so it's so clean but it's a little bit
difficult to convey that via the audio
medium to the listeners so what we're
going to do is we're going to hop into
misconfigurations we're going to talk
about misconfigurations as much as we
can um until we start needing some of
that requisite Knowledge from the first
article then we'll go back hit that and
then we'll finish up the
misconfigurations which are most um
relevant to the bug Hunters does that
sound good am I crazy yeah perfect okay
all right all right cool so let's let's
do it all right so we're g to start with
um a little bit about Don purify
correct me where I'm wrong on this and
then I'll I'll you can kind of take the
explanation a little further D purify is
an HTML sanitization Library the the
premier HTML sanitization Library um and
essentially what it allows you to do is
take untrusted user input sanitize it
and then put it into the Dom and this
should allow you if the the
configurations in Dom purify should
allow you to do that without fear of um
xss occurring from that that HTML
sanitization um and there's some there's
some questionable defaults I think in in
D purify with style and with form and
stuff like that but by default it should
pretty much clean everything up
um is there anything do you have
anything else you want to say on like
what Dom purify does and how it
functions and what makes it unique as an
HTML sanitizer um yeah probably because
I think don't said is very special
because by default cure 53 which is the
the company which has developed them
perfi MH try to provide not only a basic
sanitizer but one which allows by
default as as much stuff as they Co low
so what a task man what a task like they
could have tried to Simply put a
sanitizer which only only allows like H
tag or I don't know I don't know but
actually they do allow theion m space
the mmlm space the HML m space and I
think that this is probably one of the
only HML sanitizer that actually allows
that it's crazy ambitious them to do
that man it really is yeah um so yeah
it's used all over the place we see it
everywhere um very very cool project
that cure 53 put out I have so much
respect for those guys um really they
they do an amazing job um and one of the
other things that makes D purify unique
is it can be run on the server side and
the client side right yeah um so is it
more common for us to see it on the
server side is it more common for us to
see it on the client side you know when
you're approaching D purify re from a
research perspective and also as a book
Bounty Hunter you know what what have
you seen what what's your experience
with that been um actually most of the
time I think it's being used on the
client side um I did try to see some
statistics like on npm the number of CLE
download and like on CDN but actually if
you look at npm it's represent both
Clans side and site us and on CDN you
can't really have the number of
application that are currently using it
because you just have the number of
individual conviction yeah um but 800
million
monthly holy that'se crap that's
insane but yeah since PRI can only be
used on a JavaScript backend I think
that's probably mostly being used on the
clan site yeah yeah that that makes
sense it dude let me just say to the
listeners as well like perhaps for you
guys as you're listening wherever you
are whatever you're doing you know it
just sounds like a good episode right
you know you listen to the episode
you're like wow that's a great episode
this episode is so well prepared Kevin
thank you for going into the dock here
and do it like I just threw a question
in there I said more common server side
or client side and he like breaks down
grabs all the CDN statistics the npm
statistics like the prep that went into
this is amazing so thank you thank you
for doing that Kevin I have to shout you
out um thank you um okay awesome so
we're dealing with it mostly on the
client side so what what we might expect
to see with that let's say for example
let's say it's a stored xss we we um you
know we send some some HTML to the
server side it's stored in in that
format and then it comes back to the
client side you know maybe as the result
of a fetch request and we see the valid
you know uh xss payload in the response
from the server but then by the time it
hits the the Dom it's sanitized right
and that's that's like a classic
scenario where you'd be like okay yeah
there's some sanitization happening at
the at the client side level um okay I I
see where we're at there um so I guess
man there's so many ways that we could
go with this right because one of the
things that I want to ask you about is
like okay let's talk about the server
side for a second because it's so much
more impactful if we can get an xss on
the server side right like you can if
you can get an xss on like a headless
browser that's like generating an
invoice or something like that a lot of
times you have a route to ssrf and rce
um so let me ask you this if you're in a
blind scenario
it's just generating a PDF and you can
see the output physically right but but
you can't actually inspect the the Dom
how do I fingerprint whether it's Dom
purify or not is there um is that like I
don't know if that's like a crazy hard
question or not but does anything come
to your mind not not really actually
there is a trick for that that I've used
several time in B Bounty if you do have
like an htn injection in a PDF and you
don't know really what happened with
your inputs you can just use the plain
text tag
which is a deprecated tag which is going
to convert the end of the Dom as roow
text so that way you will be able to see
like the text version of your HTML input
and like that way you will be able to
see what's going to be sanitize what is
going to be replaced and I've seen a lot
of time like very bad sanitizer being
used in that context and simply by being
able to see what happen you see like
what the [__] there is an a replace it
there and need like to to update your
payload to have something working wait
wait so so and does let's say it is D
purify will the plain text tag make it
through dumb purify or is it is it in a
different environment um it it depends
because if your PDF is generated for
example with an headless browser then
the purify is going to be used uh before
the input being insert into the D so
what you are going to see is the
sanitized version of the inputs but uh
this time in
so then you can like play with the out
the text output version of the purify to
see if there is some patterns that might
fits tempy or I don't know another
sanitizer dude then start playing with
it that's a great that's a great tip
okay very cool and then when we're when
we're finger printing D purify on the
client side I see you've got another
trick here in in the in the dock
relating to the
CID aspect of the href can you tell me
about that um I might be wrong but I I
think that D purify is one on on of the
only sanitizer that allows by default
the C sh in the ashf tag Ash attribute I
think okay but honestly if you want to
see if if it is the purify on the clan
side there is so many ways to simp
Che and control F for D purify it's not
it's not ever like you haven't run into
anything where it's obfuscated or
anything like that yeah before Okay cool
so it should be pretty easy on the
client side you just control F for it
boom um if you're if you're dealing with
something you know where you can inspect
the uh the href um we we can use C if
it's like server side or if it's um uh
client side and then you you don't feel
like using your your sources tab I guess
um Okay cool so that that makes sense um
now let's go into a little bit of the
misconfiguration that that we sort of
talked about now that we kind of set set
the set the tone um so one of the things
that you said moving into this second
article
was that you sort of ended the first
article with okay now D purify security
solely relies on one Rex being executed
correctly um what is that Rex and like
why is that Rex so important to D purify
security um actually I will try to
explain it without uh needing to explain
everything that has been covered in the
first article but yeah in short when you
want to do mutation EXs most of the time
you will hide the payload within an
attribute value um so we'll need to use
um something like a command closure or
maybe a style or a title closure tag and
so are like mandatory if you want to do
a mutation EXs because those are
different contexts on the on the inside
of those tags is that the reason for
that um you can't have HTML tags inside
those um actually you do can but it's
it's like on the when you are using an
HTML sanitizer you have like two paring
so the first one is what D perf is going
to see and the second is what uh the D
is going to receive right and when you
are going to do mutation xss you want to
have a different context between the
browser and thei and the the goal in the
end is to have a context which is going
to break an HTML attributes and create
the xss
so one way of fixing it is to limit the
attrib
value and I think it's a good way
actually but it's
still like not perfectly limited because
if you find a way to bypass that Trix in
the end um the mutation is still present
okay okay so what what you're saying
there is that a lot of times the the
flow the strategy that we use to get
these mutation xss is we put HTML tags
inside of the attribute right because we
we can use those characters you know the
angle brackets that sort of thing inside
of the HTML attribute and then what we
try to cause with the mutation is that
that that attribute moving from an
attribute state to a to an actual HTML
processing State and then that's where
the mismatch occurs is that accurate
exactly okay perfect and so what Don Pur
purifi did and I I did kind of give you
an impossible mission here I'm like
explain the Red without explaining the
first but
I great answer that makes sense um and
the reason why that's so important just
trying to quickly summarize that that
first part is that um there there's a
pretty well documented way to bypass um
Dom purify if you are able to smuggle
HTML tags inside of that that Rex right
um so the Rex that they implemented is
simply to remove all HTML like tags or
maybe just a set of HTML like tags from
the attribute not exactly because K 53
still want to have something which
doesn't limit the developer at all so
that's why they haven't implemented that
STX before while uh there is a lot of
research that have already made been
made in the past so they decided to only
limit to style title and comments tags
uh which are being used in mutation xss
so you you still can use like image tag
in an attribute you won't be limited but
if you try to do something malicious it
won't work These Guys these guys are
legends man they really really do try to
go for the minimum you know secure
maximum secure but with the minimum
restrictions that you can possibly have
um super cool Okay so we've got no HTML
comments no title No style in our in our
HTML attributes um and if we can figure
out a way to not make that Rex hit then
we are good to go um to to trigger that
that uh that mutation
xss um I just need to charge my computer
excuse me oh you're good you're good
you're good we can we can cut or cannot
cut you know we'll see it's fine this
pod is very chill okay
perfect oh you're good yeah um Okay cool
so that makes sense now let's move to
the misconfigurations and some of these
misconfigurations are like clear's day
and other ones utilize this this like
Rex bypass um to to cause the mutation
um and and do trigger the excess so
first one on the list dangerous tags uh
dangerous allow lists tell me a little
bit about
um well D purify aims also to provide a
lot of ways to be configured to a web
developer so when you are using it you
can like modify which tags are being
allowed uh and which tag you want to add
to the default allo list so s are
commonly used but most of the time you
won't see any dangerous tag because U
obviously the developer w't allo like a
script tag but sometimes who knows maybe
um they could be used in a way that uh
they shouldn't be used um so you have we
have the list on the dock uh maybe you
want me to to site them yeah yeah let me
let me go ahead and share my screen as
well I probably should be sharing
sharing my screen sorry Christian uh my
my video editor is always like dude just
share your screen so we can give these
people some visuals um okay let me let
me jump
to this yeah so what have we got here in
in the yeah what is the default allow
list
here uh um I could give you the link but
it's present on the the pry source code
okay gotcha so the default allow list is
pretty is pretty liberal um see
yeah almost every HML tag are being
allowed like except maybe script no
script I frame or um dungo stuff like
that but right okay and and so when they
so we have these these several
configuration settings that are passed
into Don purify allowed tags allowed
attributes add tags add attributes okay
so if if we're using allowed tags or
allowed attributes we are overwriting
the default list um and allowing uh only
these specific tags so you're sort of
limiting the amount of tags that are
there how on the other hand if we're
using add tags or add attributes then
that's adding it to the already default
allowed list and creating making the
policy a little bit more LAX is that
accurate exact exactly exactly cool and
and I think I don't know now that I'm in
here I'm remembering it um but yeah I
think it was right here dude this this
is what I'm talking about Kevin when
when I am reading articles this is
exactly the kind of [__] that I want to
see okay so um in the beginning of of
this article I should have put this
before we started in the
misconfigurations he says Hey guys here
is what you should do if you're ever
looking at a dum purify misconfiguration
and he gives you a string to search for
that will just take you directly to the
beginning of the sanitized function in D
purify and that sanitized function you
if you just inspect that sanitize
function you can easily grab out the
configuration values that are being
passed into Dom purify and then like
that is just such a valuable tip okay
like it's just amazing because it
creates an easy entry point you don't
have to sour jump through all the code
it's always you're always going to go to
the same spot if it's non pufy you're
going to set a a break point or a log
point right at the beginning of that
sanitized function and then you inspect
the configuration values and look for
any of these misconfigurations that
we're talking about further down in the
in the article so awesome stuff there
obviously the the ways you can shoot
yourself in the foot with the dangerous
allow list would be like allowing
something like script uh or like onload
or anything like that for the attributes
um is there anything else sort of that
we should be on the lookout for with
these allow tags allow attributes um
configurations um I don't think so uh
because because anyway even if you allow
tag it will be sanitized by D purify in
the end so it needs to be a tag that's
have a direct impact with the Dum like
ifame Source dog or something like
that okay solid yeah that makes sense
okay and then later down in that same
section you're talking about um the
default setting for da purify which is
pretty pretty liberal like we talked
about is allow data attributes and allow
ARA attributes so essentially you can
set any attribute as long as it starts
with data equals or ar equals um why are
they doing that and why is that
important to know for bypassing D purify
um I think why why they are doing it is
um
like everything that they are doing with
them purify they want to have something
flexible and why this is important in
the context of BG Bounty well I there is
an example in right um after this uh
this snippet but there is a lot of HTML
uh
gadgets which can be found like with ugs
which is present on Ruby framework by
default I think yeah by default on Ruby
yeah and yeah a lot of data attributes
can be abused to like hijack some
JavaScript flows and trigger on xss
which don't pery won't be able to
see yeah the data attributes I think
I've seen this a couple times uh I think
it was with um with Johan Johan Carlson
doing some research um that one of the
best ways to buy pass in a highly CSP
environment I think we actually talked
about it when he came on the Pod um is
these are these sort of gadgets right
where it's like okay I can't I can't run
script you know unsafe inline or
anything like that but I can you know
add something to the Dom with a specific
data attribute or whatever and there's
something some Observer sort of watching
the Dom and saying okay when this get
gets added we're going to trigger some
some code right and then it just becomes
a gadget hunting where where you're like
okay you know what can I add to the Dom
that changes the state of the Dom that
changes the state of my specific tag
that triggers some code that
accomplishes a malicious purpose um and
I think uh if I remember correctly uh
Dom logger Plus+ is one of the the best
ways to sort of find these gadgets right
so like have you have you um because you
can you can hook after something's been
added to the Dom in particular right can
you can you talk a little bit about that
um yeah I've made a um a configuration
which will be available on the GitHub
which basically aim to start logging
everything which is happening after a
specific um event have been triggered
within the D so it could be like you
start log in when your inputs reach the
documents and that way you will be sure
that you won't have any post positive
when you are auditing some codes so you
say okay I'm there's going to be a tag
there's going to be an an a tag with the
data Dash Justin is checking something
you know ID and then we hook that into
logger and then everything as soon as
that element hits the then logger will
start going you know and it'll start
it'll you like you like how my brain
thinks about this and then D logger is
gonna
go um and then Dom logger will start
logging everything and then we'll we'll
uh be able to see what is happening
after that that hits the Dom so we can
find um those gadgets okay cool there
there is also something which could be
interesting to look for the Auditors
which is the JavaScript event
delegation um so basically there is
several ways to create an event in
JavaScript one one way is simply to put
the event on a specific tag like uh the
UN click
events but another way which is um
exactly what ugs is actually doing under
the hood is you will put the unclick
event on the document and at the time
you click on the body you will check all
the um event. Target
nodes and check if one of those nodes
have a specific attribute or whatever
and the main difference with um the
first way to set an an event is that the
you can have like an HTML injection
which occurs after the the event have
been
created because anyway the event is
present on the documents when when when
you are going when you're going to click
on the the n in the end it will simply
check if it has the property that you
want him to have to trigger the events
so so I guess maybe is this what's
happening
when I'm not sure if I if I tracked with
that but I'll try um is this what's
happening when I'm like oh okay I've got
like this button I want to see what
happens when I click this button so I
like go into Dev tools and I click on it
and then I go to like events and stuff
like that and I try to find the click
event and then there's nothing there
right yeah probably what's happening is
is the click event is actually happening
at a higher level and then it's it's
saying okay what's the target of that
event oh it's this button now I'm going
to register that that call back is that
dude I've always wondered why that was
happening I'm like how are they
triggering something if there's no on
click event that makes that makes sense
though yeah because when you click on
the page it's going to trigger the event
on all the elements that are related to
that action so putting the event on the
document walks and this is why um you
are able to abuse the ugs gadget
actually because when the page loads ugs
is probably one of the first thing which
is actually being
executed um but even if your HTML
ejection happened at the end you still
be able to abuse it because this is how
actually the event is being used dude
that's that is really helpful that is so
helpful Kevin dude this episode is
already amazing
I'm hyped um I learned so much stuff
already um okay any any final comments
on this um on this dangerous allow list
section of the
misconfigurations um I don't think so
okay let's move on to the next one then
dangerous URI attribute configuration
and when I saw this dude I was like hell
yeah a Rex you know like like this is
what we love to see as as um as hackers
it's like wow if there's a Rex people
always mess that up um and it it's
interesting too
because I don't know if this was
intentional or not but like um the
allowed URI rejects that you put in the
thing you know it it has the unescaped
dot there and I whenever I see a DOT
with without a backslash in it I'm like
triggered you know obviously it has
doesn't have the uh the carrot or the
the dollar sign as well which is what
you exploited here but it's is whenever
I look at this Rex which um for anybody
who's listening on audio only uh is
literally just you know a domain um
mizuri which is where his blog is hosted
but the dot isn't escaped my brain just
goes triggered exploit that um um so
what is this allowed URI Rex um uh
configuration that can get passed into
um D
purify um I'm not sure to understand the
question but like it allows you to
Simply overwrite which uh links can be
used um in D
purify um so basically by default the
purify has a pretty strong regx but
sometimes you might have something a bit
more custom I've seen it on several
websites and yeah I don't think that
developers understand that they are
overwriting the default value and they
might be forgetting the the dollar at
the beginning uh at the end I think at
the end um yeah there is a lot of ways
to OB it beginning okay so so so what
this does is it overrides the the URL
redx which is pretty strict although it
does include the C thing that we
mentioned before um that that's default
to to um Dom purify whenever it's put in
like an href or something like that and
the example that that we have here is
they just provided their you know you
just provided your domain which I could
totally see happening right they could
be like oh I just popped my uh my
headphone cord out um but I could
totally see that happening right where
it's like ah I only want this to be able
to point specifically towards my domain
no other links to any other sites on
thisf but what they a holistic reject to
the the dollar or the carrot at the
beginning the little upward arrow and
the dollar sign at the end in order to
match that whole whole flow so what you
did to exploit that was you put
Javascript colon alert one and then you
just get commented out the rest of the
line and then put in the value that they
wanted to see and that matches the Rex
which allowed you to um pass through a
malicious uh hre into your a tag um that
that that makes sense um and and then is
this only is this reject only for the
ahref um attribute or is this used in
other places as well uh no it's for
every um like U attributes um so the H
attribute of the Ed tag is going to be
involved as well uh the P action I
think yeah every attribute needs to have
a um a u are going to be impacted okay
very cool and then what is this um ad U
safe attribute uh setting um it's mostly
the same honestly I never saw this being
used somewhere but it was important to
be to be mentioned um so this this
option allows you to say hey um that
specific attributes is not safe and you
don't need to check it anymore oh okay
so basic just don't worry about it we
got yeah exactly wow you just downgrade
the sanitization in some place like s
that's that's a that's an easy one to
look out for and all of these will be
present in that sanitized function when
we put that that break point you know at
the beginning of the sanitized function
dude this is this is easy man you make
it too easy Kevin you know one of the
things we talked about on the Pod before
and I even shouted you out for this um
was that there there are a lot of
hackers um that have done this really
cool thing where they have become the
go-to person for one thing right classic
example of that is Alex Chapman who is
the the go-to guy for anything headless
browser right and I think you've done
the same thing for Dom purify you know
if the five got a Dom purify scenario
I'm just like yep it's goingon to go to
Kevin right now but now Kevin I can just
load up meu. re and look at this
methodology and you made it too easy to
to know how to bypass um Dom purify but
uh really do appreciate the the the
contribution to the Community um yeah
okay so let's let's go to this next one
I think there is something important to
be mentioned because since the beginning
we saying that it's you can easily
retrieve the option pass to um document.
sanitize call but it's important to
remind that each time the puy is being
used it might have a different
configuration like I've seen it a lot of
time uh we even abused this once with
matm uh on bug but um yeah it's not
because you see a specific configuration
that is safe that the next call will be
safe as well so it would be interesting
then to be able to do like a Dom logger
um Plus+ hook at that sanitized function
and I and I told you that before and you
told me some problem with that and I
can't remember what it was what was that
problem actually there is some way to
hook the sanitize function like you can
hook for a dum parel prototype uh
passform string which is used to pass um
the HTML in the end so you will be able
to see when your HTML input is being
passed um but if you want to retrieve
the configuration the problem is that
dumy could be initialized anywhere
within the JavaScript and actually it's
almost impossible to retrieve a local
variable which is uh use somewhere you
do you don't have information about yeah
that that's interesting because right
like even if we did something like okay
one the first lines I think and this is
how you you find the sanitize thing is
like doing a string replace even if we
override the string replace function to
do something that we're going to do it's
you can't jump up that extra call in in
in the stack to go into the the okay to
get access to the local variables in the
Dom lugger plus plus sanitization or the
um D purify sanitization function okay
yeah that's tricky okay so mean you kind
of have to do it a little bit manually
um each time yeah you can simply use the
lck point at the beginning of the
sanitized function and just look into
your Dev tools if there is any
configuration that are being used I'll
done yeah that that makes sense okay
cool let's jump into this next one um
bad usage not enough context as I
understand this this is not using D
purify how it's intended to be used um
and essentially it's adding
some like text area or some no script
style XMP you listed a bunch of tags
here that that could affect how Dom
purify will be able to effectively
sanitize the user input
um before you know after in appending
that after the sanitization already
occurs um is that accurate and what have
you seen this often this seems like this
would be really really common um
honestly I've mostly I've seen it in CTF
challenge um but I still believe that uh
having sanitized inputs which finish in
a title tag might be possible just
people absolutely don't look into the
title tag because they assume that it is
safe most of the time I
think um but yeah the problem is that
when you're using D purify mostly on the
server site you will provide him only
parts of the body as a context so we you
will like sanitize the the user input
but that user input is going to finish
some with in the page and when the
server responds um to the browser with
the worldall page that time the browser
will pass everything at once and yeah if
you put like the output of the fire of
something in into something dangerous
then uh you might break everything okay
so the reason why this is bad in the
specific scenario is um the the code
that you gave here was that it sanitizes
the user's input and then places it
inside a text area tag um and a text
area tag prevents the the actual uh
content inside of it from being parsed
as a HTML tag up until the ne the closed
text area tag so it's just it's
considered to be plain text so then what
we do we pass in a um a div that has the
ID or whatever other approved attribute
of closed text area and then whatever
our xss payload is that will be
permitted inside the attribute because
the you know they've got to be super
permissive with their with their
attributes exactly actually this since
3.1.3 it doesn't work anymore with style
and title as we said at the beginning
but they still have decided to leave
text area scripts and also stag being
allowed in an attributes because they do
want to have something uh which don't
limit the the develop on the end wow
yeah that's amazing so then so then when
it when it is added to the Dom with the
text
the the div tag which we pre previously
had it is just plain text it's not a
it's not a a tag so the the ID attribute
isn't being processed up until you know
the closed text area and then our image
tag that precedes that directly is being
parted as HTML and that's why the bypass
works okay cool so the the tldr of all
that is look at where your specific
sanitized output is being placed and try
to manipulate the the the payload that's
going through um uh Dom purify I keep on
wanting to say Dom logger because why
are they so similar Kevin um the payload
that's going through Dom purify to
actually fit that context that it that
it's in that that may allow for some
additional
bypasses okay solid solid any anything
else um that the user should know about
in this specific session I see some
stuff with uh with Json here um this one
is a bit more specific but
it's not working anymore on the latest
version it was a bug that I did found in
bug Bounty um but I think it's still
interesting um it was a case where Dum
perfi was used twice in a row with a
user input and US inputs right next to
each other that I feel like that should
be pretty common yeah exactly and what
you can do in uh such specific version
is thanks to the first HTML injection
you hijack the document get element by
to this time um puts an A V tag so now
the second D purify sanitize is going to
be used not in the HTML name space but
within the Ed Vision name space and
thanks to that before D purify 3.2 you
was able to Simply bypass it just
because it was using it twice a little
bit of like I it's not necessarily dumb
clobbering but it's like a little bit of
like a query selector or a get element
by ID selector um hijacking uh in the
page so okay if there's multiple there's
multiple calls to D purify and you're
able to hijack one of those calls then
that may allow you to swap the name
spaces and Trigger the xss okay dude
little side tangent I love query
selector and uh get element byid
selector um hijacking that is just such
an interesting bug class and you can
trigger so many interesting pieces of
functionality with
that it's crazy it really is um all
right Le let's let's jump down into this
uh into this next one okay so we've got
bad usage replacing the output yeah dude
this is a really this is a really cool
one and I think this is a this is one
that sort of applies to um Security in
general right if you do sanitization and
then after that sanitization
you modify it in some way right further
then that that really can um affect the
Integrity of the sanitization so tell us
a little bit about the bad usage and
replacing the output misconfiguration um
actually there is two examples in that
section um the first one is related to
an old CV which have been found in
2020 um so shortly um gquery in a spe in
oldest version was uh doing some kind of
specific replacement in the HTML
function m uh to make it like um
compatible with the old
xhtml uh paring so they was making
replacement with the Slash and greater
than to force the the tag from being
closed and so when masat found that um
go 53 decided to fix it and to put some
very strict rules about that to ensure
that the perfi can't be bypassed because
of that issue because jQuery was used
almost everywhere
also and the fact is um since a lot of
uh protection have been added in D pufy
um since 2020 they they decided um
something like a year ago to remove that
protection and now thanks to the recent
bypasses if uh the application is using
J with an older version which um is
still vulnerable to that isue then it's
possible to use the r and D purify
bypasses research to bypass D purify
again wow okay so I'm if I'm looking at
this correctly it says by default since
that version the filter is deactivated
so it you are able to use this this uh
alternative close uh tag is that is that
right exactly uh okay you should be able
to see in the snippet that I'm using
style slash instead of SL style right
here okay yeah which is going to be
replaced automatically by the vulnerable
version of uh J wow okay gotcha so that
is going to be replaced with jQuery to
the actual Clos tag and that also sort
of affects that rex that that we were
talking about in the beginning ah it's
all coming dude you know I'm not gonna
lie I'm not gonna lie sometimes I go
into these episodes and I'm like man
I've read this I understand it but like
putting it into words is so hard and now
I'm starting to I'm starting to see it
so then you know what happens here is
jQuery is providing a a sort of a
replace right where you're putting in
style
slash yeah let me let me be very clear
left uh left angle bracket um style SL
right angle bracket right and so it's
not a valid Clos tag but in jQuery it's
providing a replacement and we use that
replacement to bypass the Rex that is
validating is there a Clos style tag in
the HTML at is that is that right
exactly dude that's it dude thank you
for validating me Kevin I like this half
of this episode has been you saying
something and then being me being like
wow when Kevin says it I understand it
and then I repeat it back to you and
when you tell me yes that's right my
heart is so happy um okay so that's
great so there um jQuery is doing a
mutation on this which which makes sense
um what is this other mutation that that
that happens next well on the jQuery
issue this is something that you
probably won't be able to see today
since the version is five years old now
okay but the concept is very important
like if there is any library or any
thing that happens after which do a
replacement or a normalization like a
toer case which we're going to see a bit
later then you should be able to bypass
them purify and this is exactly what uh
masat have done a second time with tin M
which is um the second issue
um so before a specific version tinam
was replacing after d purify the bum
character by an empty string and because
of that you can simply hide a payload
within a style tag or um like in latest
version uh to bypass the regx and have
the the payload working
again okay so tiny MC was doing a
replace I'm looking at this on the uh
Unicode Cod Point f f that's bite order
Mark is that is that what that is uh
yeah what what is it okay cool and then
okay dude this is so crazy so then you
you put that right in front of the of
the style cloth dude everything just
manipulates this style clothes thing
that's so hilarious um okay yeah and
then that bypasses the Rex the the all
important Rex uh that prevents the
closed style tag from being inside an an
attribute which then breaks actually
this is very interesting because um
something that um people need to keep in
mind is that D purify is like used
everywhere so on the on one one website
it might be possible to have two D
purifi version because imagine that you
using tiny MC so tiny MC has his own D
pufy version and then you are using your
own D pufy version because you aren't
using the one of them of
and this is more or less what I did try
to explain in the second example because
I found um a case in B Bounty where uh
the it is the the second one with um on
top of it oh here that that one yes this
one yeah okay I see I see um I faced a
situation in bonti where tin was using
an out upto-date version of the perfi
but thanks to the replacement I was able
to bypass it but then um the website to
fix that issue was using this time an
outdated version of
dfy um
so the fact is that you can like bypass
Dy map even if it's used several time in
a hoe and more interestingly I faced the
case where there is two D purifies used
in a hole but this replacement was um
used twice as well the problem is
the problem is
like you can't put uh like for example a
new line within a new line so at the
first placement um you really lose your
Gadget to bypass the second on purify
but you can use the fact that the Dum
decodes by default um HTML entities to
hide from the first replacement uh the
new line which going to to appear after
the first pufy sanitizing um which then
going to create um the the right
replacement to bypass them pery a second
time dude that that is amazing
and that makes total sense so you know
you can't split a new line like a lot of
times I think of a new line character as
back sln because I I like that's how
I've always seen it you know um and I
was like oh you could just do backs
slash backs slash n n but that's not
that doesn't work you know it's just
such a for a second your brain's like
wait a second no no no that's not right
but yeah absolutely using some sort of
encoding here to sort of um space that
out that's that's genius I love that um
and using the auto auto decoding of HTML
um
entities very cool man okay so now that
that sort of and you listed a bunch of
other examples on how Dom purify has
been bypassed and and with other you
know misconfigurations or bypasses uh
but that sort of concludes the first
section which is uh the the
misconfigurations that you commonly see
um and now we move into um D purify
hooks which is a a little bit of a newer
um feature to D purify and it allows uh
if I understand correctly and and uh it
it allows the developer to hook into the
sanitization process at various points
and when there's more configuration like
this there's more problems so um can you
tell us a little bit about those hooks
and where where they can be used to
bypass stuff uh yes so those are present
within thei since a long time okay
they're not but the fact is that um in
the context of um sanitization
configuration it will be applied for One
D purify sanitize call at the opposit a
d purify hooks are defined to configure
Dum purify more globally so they will be
present each time you do a sensitization
with that DFI instance okay and because
of that there is like no direct way to
to find S hooks except
by searching within the JavaScript files
and I think that's one of the reason why
people probably haven't um look at them
a lot um since today uh because you you
have to know that they exist actually
and you have to search for them directly
because they're not going to be in that
standartized call okay um so there is
many ooks um but shortly what you need
to keep in mind is that all the time you
have three hooks for the sanitized
element timing three hooks for the
sanitized attribute timing and three HS
for the sanitized Shadow Dum timing
Shadow sorry every time I hear that in
my brain I'm just like and then the
Shadow do like that's that's hilarious
I'm sorry okay so uh three three hooks
for element sanitization three hooks for
attribute sanitization three hooks for
shadow on sanitization y okay before
upon and after
exactly okay and and so um these hooks
allow you to change the current the
current configuration the settings um
manipulate the the things being
sanitized as they go through that
specific um flow a and help me help me
understand how D purify does the
sanitization is it like starting with
the top node and then like going down to
the to the first child and then does it
go all the way through through that that
whole chain and then work its way back
up or what what does that flow look like
um if we go directly into the technical
details it used first Dum passer which
is an API provided by the brow browsers
to pass HTML okay um thanks to this it
will obtain a tree and it will retrieve
by default only the body this is
something I abuse later in the article
but it retrieve only the body and then
it's going to use the N iterator IPI
which allows to create something on
which you can do a for Loop and you will
simply like iterate over each nod of the
tree but um it takes the nod on the top
of the tree and um iterates down the
tree to finish with the one at the
bottom okay so does it does it start
sanitizing at the innermost node or does
it start sanitizing at the at the top
node at top node at the top node okay so
it sanitizes goes to the child sanitizes
goes to the child okay gotcha and does
that recursively dude actually it makes
a lot of sense um when you said it just
takes the body I know you used that
later um to with the Bas tag that was
such an amazing misconfiguration but
that also makes me understand why the
metatag bug Works do do you know what
I'm talking about where you can set like
um a metatag referral policy it have you
seen that yes yeah so Jrock mentioned
that on his episode uh I'll have to go
back and find the episode number maybe
the production team can put it on the
screen if they want to um but
essentially what happens is you can pass
a metatag into Dom purify and that
metatag will get stripped out right for
sure but the effect that it has on the
Dom is still present somehow um it like
and I don't as I'm saying it I was like
oh that makes sense because it's being
passed into the dawn parser but when you
apply a metatag to the the D parser then
it applies it to the main D now it's not
making sense again do do you do you
understand um I'm not sure but okay
actually shouldn't be applied on the
main but maybe that isn't the place
where it where it's uh where it's
triggered
then but it should be applied within the
Dum which is created by Dum passer and
I'm not really surprised to hear that it
do work in the context of D purify or
any D passer API because when you using
D parer you simply create a dum the same
way the Brer will do when he receive an
HTP request like it's exactly the same
and this is why most of the time you
want to use a sanitizer on the client
side because you are going to use the
same parer at the beginning and at the
end of um the input us AG
so yeah I'm not really surprised and the
other point as I was saying about the
body is that if you put the metat tag at
the very beginning the purify won't be
able to see it at all because by default
when you pass an HTM in puts and you
have like a style tag or a meta tag at
the beginning it will be placed in the
head tag which is retrieve and stize by
D pufy but will have an effect on all
the nodes that are PR present after dude
that's that's pretty hacked up to be
honest that they that they only look at
the body that they don't consider what
is in the head I bet I bet there's more
bypasses that could be done there
because you can
manipulate what the the yeah I mean
obviously there is because you did it
with the base tag all right let's let's
keep going we'll have time for that but
but let's keep going through um through
what you have and then I'll I'll geek
out about that later okay so um the
first section that you had here was uh
the upon sanitized attribute so we and
I'm sorry let me just refresh my memory
on the order so it goes sanitize element
sanitize attribute sanitize Shadow Dom
um just for can you give me like a two
second uh description of what sanitize
sh
does um or is that not a two second
description No it should be fine like it
should go in the D J sod it's like um
there is okay it won't be two
secondly but there is something really
important to know like when you're using
the N iterator IPI there is something uh
which isn't handled by default by the
browser is that when you iterate a dum
when it reach um a shadow dum it won't
go through the shadow D so basically if
you create a sanitizer which only used
the N iterator
IPI like you will miss a lot of tags and
there will be a lot of bypass just
because of that because they'll be
hidden in the shadow do okay that's it
so so D purify is simply like taking the
shadow D creating a new iterator
function out of it and at the beginning
and at the end of that new function they
are putting some hooks to add the
developers to to do some stuff okay
gotcha so the flow is sanitize elements
sanitize attribute if it's a shadow Dom
sanitize the shadow is that right that's
it okay cool so then um we talking about
the first configuration it's the upon
sanitized attribute so this is while the
attribute is being sanitized itself um
and you say that there's a
misconfiguration there with the force
keep attribute can you tell us about
that um well I think that this specific
o is probably one of the most used ooks
in the perfi because this is the only
one that allows a developer to have both
a nod and a reference to specific
attributes within the
sanitization and the the funny the funny
stuff that uh was present in dumy
3.1.3 up to
3.1.5 is that when they do implemented
the rigex
then puted the rig X after the uh for
skip attributes value which was being
used by that specific
book so in short developers was able to
say to D pufy hey um that specific
attribute is completely safe I want you
to do not sanitize it and right after
the pufy was simply skipping it but the
regx check wasn't be made at all so if
there was any attribute which was
allowed by default by the developer than
to that ook you was able to bypass pufy
onour version okay okay so Force keep
attribute I I wonder if that's a little
bit of a misnomer because I like or if
the name is a little bit weird because
what I would think if it was force keep
attribute was do not remove this
attribute doesn't necessarily mean do
not sanitize it at all like is that does
it mean do not sanitize it at all it's
more do not sanitize it at all wow okay
gotcha yeah so that even just the naming
convention on that is a little bit like
a little bit unsure about that and I and
I would imagine that um yeah like even
even if you wanted to say you know for
these specific data attributes or
something like that yeah I need this
specific data attribute to go through
and a user can control even a part of
that you say okay you know what force
force this attribute to stay there and
then that skips the whole Rex which once
again breaks all of Dom purify um okay
so we should be on on the lookout for
any use of force keep attribute but it
it has to be on specific version because
this is something I've reported to c53
so why Why did no it's important it is
it is is very important I just you know
my first instinct is damn it Kevin why
uh but then my second my second instinct
is like no no Justin secure the
internet um Okay cool so that that works
well the example on Dro I think it's a
great one which um helps to understand
why do a developer will have to use that
um it's a bit on the bottom uh is it
further down here uh yeah that one on
the um the snip it on the bottom of your
screen this one right here yeah okay
cool I think this is a great example
because um when you do want to sanitize
for H VG contents or I don't know for
example the Ed tag with the H effect
attributes m you might want to put some
very specific sanitization process on S
because they they're like special and
you know that bad things can happen
because of that so you don't want to
Simply allow the use ashref elements so
sometimes web developers could um want
to use ooks to put a more specific logic
to under it in the way they want to
under it and this is where um dra was
vulnerable in the the snipet present in
the screen um they was simply like
making sure that D perfi do not sanitize
the content attributes and because of
that uh it was possible to bypass it
yeah man if there's so literally the
condition is if force force keep
attribute is is there and you control
arbitrarily even a part of the content
of that attribute just those two
conditions definitely
bypass dude I love that I love that and
I also love that you said that you said
um this upon sanitized attribute is like
one of the ones that that's use the most
right like that is the kind of [__] that
you need to hear from like an expert
that's like yeah I think that's the one
that you know that's the one we pay
attention to that we're really like you
know if if there's one that you walk
away from and you actually store in your
hacker brain rather than having to
reference back to the article then it
might be upon um sanitize attribute that
that that's really good um I also love
how you just casually dropped
the dryo zero day here that's that's
great actually it's not really a zero
day because this is something I've
reported to to
you no that's that's great um all right
uh let let's move to this next one once
again another upon sanitized attribute
um bypass and this one occurs when
you're using current node. set
attributes so essentially you're adding
attributes to the attri to the element
that have already been
um is being
sanitized um this one is I think way
more interesting than the previous one
because this is something pure 53 can't
fixed at all so it still works in the
latest version um but in short um when
um D pufy sanitize an attributes it will
like um take the nod retrieve the
attributes
attribute then it will iterate over each
attribute present within it and um then
is going to like sanitize it and call
the open sanitize attribute hook but the
fact is because the attributes has been
retrieved before iterating over the
attributes obviously if you add an
attribute within that Loop it won't be
verified at all by don't
verify and if it's not being verified
it's not being verified by the regx so
you can like by the holy reg okay gotcha
so so what's what's happening here then
is it's loading up a list of all the
attributes first into like a a local
array and then it's iterating across all
of them doing the sanitization and then
because you're adding things after that
it's it's not getting caught in that
first these are all the attributes for
the specific node and then okay I see
what's happening here yep that's buggy
but I wonder you know you said this is
something that that um maybe uh the
folks over at 53 can't resolve um but I
I'm thinking what if just after the
first iteration across all the well then
you'd have to do it recursively forever
yeah yeah no it's not gonna
happen that's crazy all right so then
you add another attribute so any use uh
use of current node. set attribute or is
there a way to add attribute here uh not
that I see I'm sure there is but I guess
that attribute could be used in the same
way um then and you control any part of
that then you can trigger that same
bypass that's it and I've seen a lot of
um HTML uh editors that was simply like
taking all the dangerous um attribute
that they do not know and like only
setting a new attributes which was
prefixed with data so that way they they
were sure that this was being safe but
simply because they was doing that um
the sanitization was just broken don't
don't mess with dom purify man like
don't try to make D purify more secure
like they've got it it's like shooting
yourself in the foot it's like rolling
your own crypto um okay awesome and yeah
here's that that use of that same
mutation xss that we talked about um
before the call um gotcha that yeah and
you know the thing is I would like to to
go in and we're already at like an hour
15 minutes which is blew by um so I'm
not sure we're going to be able to get
to the full research you know
explanation section um this time around
but uh there are so many gadgets that I
think are really helpful you've
mentioned two of them already you know
the fact that it parses the body only
the body not the head of that Dom and uh
and then you know the usage of how
bypassing Dum purify is very
proceduralized with like the the xss or
the mutation xss um being triggered via
the the title style or HTML comments
tags um those I think are really helpful
and I think you also included a section
at the end of your article that talks a
little bit about areas of research that
that can continue as well um so for the
for anybody who's interested in
continuing research or having a little
bit more deep of understanding on how
all this works I'll refer you to meu. um
domain to to sort of uh read through
that um but let's go ahead and cover the
these
um remaining hooks we we'll dip into
them miscellaneous section A little bit
and then we'll we'll we'll call it a
wrap because it's we're already an hour
15 in um so let let's talk about before
sanitize attribut so this is happening
after the sanitization of elements this
is happening before the start of the uh
attribute sanitization and apparently if
there's some uh attribute manipulation
happening here that can result in a
problem um well manipulation can be like
whatever you want it could be a
replacement it could be a change and if
there is something like that which
happens on the ID attributes
specifically um then you should be able
to do some kind of sign sign order Dum
cling which was a concept I have used in
the first article but uh basically as
you can see on the Dum Explorer window
on the bottom um if there is a
normalization like um a trim or a
replacement you can have a form which
has an ID with um a value set to Space X
and an unload attributes so at the time
Dy is going to sanitize it and check for
Dum clubing issue because there is a
space within the ID um D pufy will don't
find any Dum cling D cling issue and the
the tag is going to be left but at the
time the normalization occurs in the
before sanitize attributes then you can
recreate a link between uh the form type
and the input tag so in that case by
removing the space and because of that
you can now clubber um the form tag
before the attributes being
retrieved and thanks to that you will be
able to force them purify to iterate not
over the form attributes but over the
input attribute the input tag okay and
that
way just won't see the the unload events
okay okay okay
so confusing that that's confusing I'm
sorry I'm sorry to
take but but um so so what you're saying
is you know we've got a form ID Space X
right then we got another input tag form
equals x right so it's associating with
that specific form um and so when the
Dom purify is reaching into the Dom to
sanitize this attri I mean it's not
I'm I'm confused as to why this is
resulting in
ah ah because attributes okay okay I see
I see what's happening here is a little
bit hard to expl yeah yeah let's go back
and explain that piece maybe I should
have explain uh the form attribute
actually um so the form attribute can be
used on input tags or select tags or
whatever which is related to a form and
that attribute is very interesting
because it allows you to link your input
tag to a form in which you aren
into so this can be used in a lot of
ways but in the context of D
purify what you can do is force this
link to be created after the Dum cling
check uh been made so then thanks to the
normalization the ID value and the form
value value will be equivalent which
will create a link between the form tag
and the input tag and the time that link
is being created the Dum Club ring is
going to occure so now thanks to this
you control the form. attributes value
and because the pufy is ring that that
value without doing any Dum clubing
checks you kind like break the
sanitization for that form
specifically that rocks dude that rocks
so much so so so what's happening here
okay this is like requires a little bit
of pre- knowledge of of Dom clobbering
right and and we typically you know on
this podcast we we try not to go back
too far into the requisite knowledge
that you need um because that gets a
little cumbersome uh but this time I
think it it's helpful so in in the Dom
clobbering World using a form and an
Associated input tag is a is a way for
you to create
um to clobber attributes that are
several elements deep so X do attributes
in this specific scenario right um and
but but that only occurs if the input
tags form attribute is pointing to the
ID of the form that it is being
associated with right and so what's
happening here is when that um specific
ID is being trimmed right that's what's
happening in the code and the ID goes
from space X to just X that is when it
creates the link between the form and
the input and and allows us to override
the attributes dude that's his Kevin
this is freaking genius man this is
genius genius um very cool and the
amount of detailed knowledge of the the
Dom purify source code that is required
for this is like really really cool how
does how does um let me ask you this a
little bit derailed but how does Dum
purify deal with those Dum clobbering
issues
typically um actually they are using um
a is valid attributes function I think
that's the name at the beginning of the
sanze element function and in short they
check if the current node is a form and
if it is a form it will check if for
example the attribute value has a
specific type which is supposed to be um
a ND name I think um elements um if for
example it check the N name it will be
sure that it is a string Etc so it just
verify the type of all the dangerous
attributes that can be present on the
form and if they find something
malicious they remove the
form Kevin dude it's just unbelievable
that I can just ask you about a specific
like section of the Dom purify code and
the procedure that they're using to
sanitize and just off the top of your
head you can rattle off like how exactly
they're they're doing that that is um
that is unbelievable this is what I'm
talking about just a word to the
listener really quick this is what I'm
talking about when I'm saying you should
become the world expert on a specific
piece of technology right like when
you're hacking something you have to
know it inside outside upside down even
more so true if you're trying to bypass
a security oriented Library like this
but even the applications that you face
from day to day the targets that you're
going up against you need to know that
implica that application inside outside
upside down so where you can rattle off
the you know the specific procedure
that's used for you know whatever on
that specific app so this is a perfect
example of that um all right and it even
helps when you want to like uh try to
find bug why you aren't in front of your
computer of your mobile phone because
you can simply like think about
everything that uh you have memorize and
say hey there there is something that I
didn't expect and now you want to try
but yeah you can continue to think um
anytime and I think that make the
difference actually yeah 100% because
it's all in there right and you can run
simulations in your brain you can be
walking down the street and be actively
hacking like that that's something that
my my wife and and stuff doesn't
understand sometimes which is like I'm
sitting there I'm playing piano right
the like this desk right here that's
behind me typically has a piano on it
like you know because I sometimes when
I'm I'm working and stuff I gotta like
get up and like play some piano or
whatever and I'm sitting there playing
the piano and I'm thinking about where I
am in the code base and where the the
flow of data looks like and what access
to inputs and outputs I've got and it
just you know you can hack Whenever
Wherever that's that's a great Point
Kevin
guys I don't know time podcasts like
these just get me so jazzed up about B
Bounty like what a dream career we have
guys where we get to just hack stuff
every day ah I love it um all right rant
over rant over um let's talk about uh
after sanitize attribute and then some
string replacement or attribute
manipulation what is what is this one
Kevin so this one is mostly the same as
we have seen with uh the tiny MC MC ISU
and DG query isue um like if there is
any kind of manipulation or replacement
occurring in the um after sanitized
attributes ook because it happens after
the RX checks being made um any
manipulation can be dangerous actually
um so I'm just providing a first example
which is uh just a replacement to Mt um
but this could be anything that mod the
value actually I think the second
example is more interesting like the
super case the second example is super
interesting I I love this and I love it
when things the stars align for stuff
like this so yeah let's get to that but
um first the thing that you said was
that uh if if after sanitized attribute
occurs there is some modification to the
attribute right after sanitization we're
modifying that's where we kind of get
into the issues like we talked about
before specifically this happen when you
are replacing something to nothing
because you can create structures that
shouldn't have been allowed to exist
during the sanitization cool now this is
the crazy [__] right here take it away
Kevin
so this is something I I don't know if
it's well known but when you are using
the two uppercase method or the two
lowercase in every language it's not
related to JavaScript um there is some
Unicon normalization that occurs so
there is few chars which are going to be
converted to the as equivalent and in so
tag in so chars luckily there is one
which converts an unic unical Char to St
so thanks to this if the attribute is
being to aase you can like add um a
style tag from the regex which is going
to then be converted to the ask equal
because of that normalization dude that
is I want to I want to know what the
code point for this is okay it's Unicode
code point
009c that that uh
gets like normalized to an st when it
goes to uppercase and I think there's
another one here too there's two that
kind of U when they go to uppercase
convert to St what a gift from Heaven
that is right like that we that we have
out of these like what is there like 10
15 characters that actually conver to
something uh you know completely
different when they are uppercased one
of them goes to St which is exactly what
we need for a style tag oh my gosh dude
that's amazing okay so then somebody's
just simply doing an innocent two
uppercase on the contents of this
attribute and we can use that to bypass
um D purify by creating a style
attribute which is one of those ones
that we're not allowed to have in the
attribute is that right exactly
man the hits keep coming man this that
that is very cool and and yeah I think
for anybody who is listening to the
podcast and did didn't know about this
um up two uppercase thing um one you
should either go back and listen to the
podcast that you haven't listened to
where we've talked about this or you
should try to take this opportunity
right now in this moment to remember
that forever because that is extremely
helpful in so many scenarios this
Unicode normalization and this alone can
really result in some crazy bounties um
you know being able to do this in a um
in a email or like a user name or
something like that can allow you to
just get atto super easy um so Unicode
normalization is definitely something
that any serious hacker web hacker in
particular should should look into I
think um all right node manipulation
insert before what is this one so this
one is mostly related to the blow D per
if I apply to sanitize an HTML
input so hasu say um it will like
iterate over the D from the top topest
not to the bottom one right y yep and so
if within any hooks the developer decid
to take a n and insert it above the
current node then this is something that
dumi won't be able to at all because
it's going to continue downward right
okay so if if it has a reference to a
specific div or something like that
that's above it maybe by an ID and you
just say insert before that boom we've
now jumped and effectively hidden that
node from D purify so it can't be
sanitized and this can bypass D purify
in many ways because um imagine that
this happens uh I don't know in the
sanitize element function um and the
inserted node isn't dangerous at all
like it's just a simple P tag that you
control but that P tag has the regx
bypass then it's enough to bypass the
dude it's crazy to see it's crazy to
look at this example here and just see
see like the Dom purify output in Dom
Explorer just be a perfect uh xss St
yeah that's crazy and like you can play
with the with the integration actually
if you want to update it uh in the bar
it's actually working in life oh dude
that freaking Dom Explorer is so cool
dude I I love I love that very cool all
right cool so we got to keep in mind the
order of um the sanitization that's
occurring and if there's any elements
being inserted into a node that has
already been sanitized then then that is
not going to get touched at all that
makes sense easy peasy um let me see how
many more of these we've got left here
uh maybe the the NN name normalization
is interesting n name case confusion is
that the one um not the base b as
pollution this one is very technical
very deep but the impact is um not
that's much and we sort of already
talked about it right this is using the
base tag to affect the the fully
qualified URLs of the um items of the
relative URLs in the body of the Dom
that is pared by Dom purify right uh yes
but but not only there is also the the
fact that I'm abusing that D purify is
trimming all the attribute values to
have like some collision between what it
is going to us and what the Dum is going
to receive but in the end this is it uh
you have a way to uh control the um
final ashf which is going to be
sanitized within the hook wow damn it
Kevin all right
fine well we'll have to come back to
that that one is very very technical I
do love the output of it though this is
just a beautiful exploit um so I'm gon
we're gonna leave that one um to the
listeners to go check out themselves and
then we'll talk about this
one this one is node name names Space
Case confusion is that the one you you
wanted to talk about yes because I think
that one is um pretty common like I've
seen it a lot of time in back Bounty
um well it it might sounds a bit stupid
but when you try to access the N name
value depending on the name space of uh
the node on which you're trying to
retrieve that value the case is going to
be different like if you try to access
nde name in the HML space it's going to
be uppercase but if you try to do the
same within the a vision space it's
going to be lower case
why I don't
know that's crazy is that something
specifically done by D purify or is that
a part of the like HTML spec uh it's
part of the HTML specification like this
is something that brows us
do node yeah of course node name okay
current we're actually we're using the
the browser wow okay so that's weird so
in and if we hit node name typically um
in the HTML name space it's going to be
uppercase but if it is in the SVG name
space then it's going to be lower case
exactly L and I've seen some application
using that specifically to sanitize
style Tye for example so to sanitize the
content and limit what the user can do
you you actually send me an example
right after reading the the article but
yeah this is something very common and
by simply putting your style tag within
the SVG tag in case it do not check it
with to upper case then you will just
bypass this condition and we able to do
a full c c CSS exfiltration wow okay so
and that output there that has SVG tag
style inside of it that's perfectly
valid HTML uh yes style tag that will
execute on the page the having it
wrapped inside of an SVG doesn't like
hijack the the functionality of it at
all um I'm sorry I'm Tred to the
question that that's fine so you know
the output here of the sanitization that
you showed is SVG um and then a style
tag right so the style tag is wrapped in
the SVG um but that doesn't affect the
functionality of the style tag at all
the the style tag still works normally
on the on the page wow very cool very
cool okay do you want to cover this last
one I know that this is like a Dom
clobbering Doss but actually let's do it
if we can because I think this you you
made a great point that Dom clobbering
inside of an HTML um parser like this or
sanitizer can have really bad effects on
applications yes um so this I think this
kind of exploitation is still very
specific like if you're trying to do dum
pufy or any JavaScript library in a page
that is unvisited at all it might be
useless but um if you manage to use Dum
clubing to like does d purify within the
chats then you will be able to BL the
conversation for all the user which is
way more impactful very impactful
and um when you are using as a developer
before sanitize elements um in D purify
this specific hook occurs before the Dum
clubing check have been made so if like
the developer use any attributes uh
function of of a nod then you can simply
clubber it on a form and dum is going to
crash okay so it it will if there's any
if there's anything being done before
sanitize elements then that is before
the Dum clobbering check so you can just
blow it up essentially wow okay that
that seems like a problem yeah I I
wonder why they didn't move the Dom
clobbering check to
before it's complicated because they
want the developer to be able to
manipulate the nut before it's being
sanitized by D purify um so I'm not very
sure there is something they can do
about that yeah I agree I agree okay um
let's jump into the miscellaneous
category here um the Rex that this is
the Rex by the way for everybody who
we've beening to the I don't know that
I've shown it on the screen yet my bad
um this is the Rex that everybody needs
to know um uh and I'm sorry for people
that are only you're just you're screwed
this time um I'm not gonna read a Rex
out loud to you um but the the code that
uses this reject is actually prefixed by
an if statement and the if statement
says if safer HTML and and Rex test
right and then goes through our Rex um
so you say you know of course if this is
uh false then we trigger the bypass so
so when does that is that a specific
configuration that can be passed in um
Yes actually I've I seen it recently
with a friend in B Bounty where um in a
library the developer was like using it
because he wasn't able to use commments
within attributes so when I first see it
I was like okay that seems legit but
yeah you just breaking the world don't
purify sanitization and yeah this is
something that is mentioned in the D
purify rme but if the developer doesn't
take it into account the fact that there
is a warning about it um then you can
bypass it easily very cool man very cool
so if they if they pass in save for XML
set to false then it's just Boom game
over you're done exactly
okay um there are a lot of other really
cool things in here y uh um let's I'm
gonna do these two I know I said that I
was gonna be done but I'm actually not
gonna be
done suck it listeners you better keep
listening because this is cool [__] okay
so all right this is it though after
this I'll I'll end it I know we're we're
going long um this misconfiguration is
really really cool and this switches
back over to the server side right this
in the scenario where we are in the
server side um and what's being done is
that there's a JS Dom that's JS Dom is
being used with with dom purify um and
jom is the recommended uh server side um
uh parser for for this to be used in
conduction with um with d purify uh but
what dude this is like really gold if
there is no content um type Char set
defined right if there's no Char set
defined for that specific which I would
imagine would happen all the time if
people are just on the Fly sanitizing
HTML they're not going to set like a
content type header or whatever um then
then this would be resulting in a full
bypass using um that sort of what is the
name of that research that that came
from
umy here let me see
it'sing been made by
but um yeah am I tripping something fun
about that research is that um this is
something I have found like one month
before sonar release everything I have
reported that to D purify and um C 53
told me that this is some not something
that they could fix this is something
that had to be reported to Google and
actually I was just sing thinking that
this is not something that was going to
be fined quickly by someone else so I
decided to play a bit with it with in B
Bounty and like something months ago I
see the world research and I was like
okay great
but unforunately W so you had it before
research Collision of course it happens
um but what this I if I if I understand
correctly this is that same research as
well that was talking about how
um you can use like one of the Japanese
character sets to to trigger is that is
that accurate right where where that one
yes isog GP 2022
right okay so what you're doing here is
you are manipulating the fact that
there's no uh Char set set on the server
side and then using
that fact to make the browser sniff the
charet and since D purify isn't aware of
that then uh in jsd then it will it will
bypass it is that accurate that's it wow
dude yeah like am I am I crazy to think
that this is going to be like super
common a super common bypass I I can't
imagine somebody setting a Char set like
that like a lot of framework by default
set a Char set nowadays um I think where
it's going to be um the more present is
in file uploads like if you can upload
for example an EDG and it's being
sanitized most of the framework when
they do send the file they won't set the
Char sets um so this should be relable
all the time ah Kevin Kevin I'm
misunderstanding What's Happening Here
the the the problem is not with so we
also have to have a Char set not defined
at the when it hits the sync on the
client side is that accurate or no um
not really it's like when the the
browser is like loading the page it do
need to not have a Char set being
defined the browser the final like the
final rendering of the payload um no I
mean the h HP
response uh in the content type respon
header it do need to not have a charet
for it to be
sniffed right but what I'm what I'm
wondering here is whether we can take so
there's two things happening here right
it's creating a new it's creating a JS
Dom right and then it loads that into D
purify and then it runs Dom purify
sanitize on that specific string right
and that specific string has um the
stuff to indicate that it's the Japanese
car set or character set and then you
know renders it and then the output of
that it does that
also need to not have a character set or
can it just can it be integrated into a
utf8 character set and it's it's fine
it's fine it's like um it's I think it's
the uh like Escape Charles which is an a
basic asy character that you need to use
to trigger the cut point to switch
between the Japanese chars and theq one
okay so this is something that is going
to be allowed most of the time by any
text parer or sanitizer like them
verified okay so I'm looking at this
code right here this this you set the
header text HTML here could this have
the utf8 character set in it or or is
that necessary to not have that um it's
not mandatory but nowadays almost every
Frameworks to have it set by default so
right so if it did have it would the
would with this clean
not work or would it or would it still
work um it won't works but there is
still some tricks that can be made like
even if the content type is set to text
HTML uh semicolon Char set equal UTF we
utf8 excuse me um there is something
funny is that um if somehow you can
control the two first bites of the
response you can use the the bomb
characters to specify the browser to
pass it as UTF 16 and even if the chart
set is defined as as utf8 it still will
work so it could be possible to be
bypassed that way but D purify do not
allows to use um like those characters
okay those cocktails okay so I guess my
question is this right here on this line
where it says clean equals D purify
sanitize and then passes in our specific
input will the output of clean after
this is done when passed to a
specific or or when passed to like a
normal browser Dom with uh text HTML
question will will that trigger an xss
or does the the the end browser also
have to have a
um good question well that depends on
the uh actual um like library that you
are using in the context of the purified
GS Dum and by default it do not execute
JavaScript MH so even if there is a way
for you to trigger JavaScript within D
purify it won't be executed at Old only
because uh this is disabled by default
okay okay but if you're using for
example a library like idom which
is this is something that can happen
Okay so they specific so they say use
jsd but if you're using something else
like happy Dom then you can trigger JS
execution inside of Dom purifi
sanitization
yes and actually this isn't how do I
manage to get an rce because obviously
the JavaScript execution occurs within
the sunbox so you can't really Escape it
but the fun fact was um that when you
provides um to that passing Library uh
scripts with a specific Source it's
going to use uh a sub process using no-
e to like petch the the file reserve it
execute it
and the link that is provided within
script source is single
quoted and why this is bad because the
within the pass and within the Anor you
can put single quotes which won't be
encoded by default within the uh URL
grac so that way I was just able to hide
um like not just code directly within my
script tools so you should be able to
see it u in the second snippet yeah
right here which are going to be
executed um directly within the library
that's crazy it's like that that um that
old flash thing this is what we always
reference in these sort of scenarios
where the way that you used to trigger
flash based xss a lot of times was was
do like just you could just close off
the it would just dump it right into a
JS eval and you could just close off all
the functions and and stuff it's crazy
that this is happening with Happy D as
well and this is something I've found a
lot in bbon like sometime the Developers
simply reflect the current pass within
uh a JavaScript variable but if you do
that um with a single quoted string like
you you can just Escape it using a
single Cote sits it's not encoded wow
that's nuts dude how do you I guess then
we go back to the fingerprinting problem
how do you figure out if they're doing
at server side what um Dom parsing
they're using like happy versus jsd that
that gets a little trickier right um
maybe if you like create a local setup
and you try to see some differences
between the HTML passing you will be
able to to find something I feel like
there's some stuff out there for that
yeah yeah all right Kevin we are an hour
45 minutes in I have this is you right
here I have squeezed you for every last
bit of wisdom that I can get on Dom
purify at least the second article um
and we still didn't even get into the
first article so um thank you so much
for coming on for sharing so willingly
about um all of this research that
you've done um yeah really really
appreciate it this is really a master
class on on Dum purify um anything you
want to say or anything you want to
shout before we we wrap this pod that's
right it's it was a pleasure from for
being there like um it was amazing
speaking about D Peri today and yeah I
think that's all I'm very happy being
there thank you so much Kevin appreciate
you brother
peace and that's a wrap on this episode
of critical thinking thanks so much for
listening and if you want more critical
thinking content head over to ctbb Dosh
show/ Discord join the Discord there's
lots of great conversations and chats
going on over there and if you want to
support the show there's the Discord
subscriber tiers which give you access
to master classes amas hack alongs
exclusive scripts and an exclusive chat
Channel with us we'll see you there